A story of an incredible friendship.
The Long Walk Home is a drama, history film directed by Richard Pearce.
Two women, black and white, in 1955 Montgomery Alabama, must decide what they are going
to do in response to the famous bus boycott led by Martin Luther King.
Miriam Thompson, played by Sissy Spacek.
Odessa Cotter, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Norman Thompson, played by Dwight Schultz.
Herbert Cotter, played by Ving Rhames.
Tunker Thompson, played by Dylan Baker.
Selma Cotter, played by Erika Alexander.
The Long Walk Home is a 1990 American historical drama film starring Sissy
Spacek and Whoopi Goldberg, and directed by Richard Pearce.
Set in Alabama, it is based on a screenplay about the Montgomery bus boycott (1955–1956) by John Cork and a
short film by the same name, produced by students at the University of Southern California in 1988.
The film explores themes of civil rights, racial
segregation, racism, 1950s, segregation.
The tone is emotional.